Hugh Bolton Jones letters
Hugh Bolton Jones letters
1880-1881
1880 1881
Coll020
Jones Hugh Bolton 1823?-
1 box (.5 linear feet)
1 box
.5 linear feet
A collection of letters addressed to Hugh Bolton Jones, father of a Maryland landscape painter who bore the same name. The most frequent correspondents are his wife Laura, his daughter Louise, and his son also named Hugh Bolton Jones. There are also several letters from Jones's business acquaintances. Because both father and son shared a name it is unclear at times who is being addressed, but the majority of the letters were intended for the senior Hugh Bolton Jones. Includes letters with envelopes and some envelopes without accompanying letters.
University of Maryland, Baltimore County Albin O. Kuhn Library and Gallery UMBC 1000 Hilltop Circle Baltimore, MD 21250 410-455-2353 speccoll@umbc.edu
The Hugh Bolton Jones letters range in date from 1880 to 1881, with three undated items. This collection of correspondence includes 20 letters with envelopes and 6 envelopes without accompanying letters, comprising .5 linear feet.
The collection contains the correspondence of Hugh Bolton Jones or his wife, Laura, from their children, relatives, friends, and acquaintances. Envelopes are addressed to Hugh Bolton Jones. Those who corresponded with Jones include Hugh Bolton Jones, their son; Louise, their daughter; Lydia A. Hamilton, a relative; [Hank] Jones, Hugh Bolton Jones' brother; Joseph F. Foreman; Francis A. Crook; and E.M. Stephenson.
The content of the letters includes personal correspondence and business relationships. Several of the letters reference an exchange of money. The bulk of the letters, however, are the private mail between child and parent. Four letters from Hugh Bolton Jones to his father include his signature, "H. Bolton Jones."
One letter in particular seems to have been written to the son, who was a well-known Maryland landscape painter; this letter describes an acquaintance's visit to a French Salon show, including descriptions of paintings by Jones and several other painters.
Born circa 1823, Hugh Bolton Jones was the father of the well-known Maryland landscape painter, Hugh Bolton Jones (1848-1927), Francis and Louise. He was married to Laura Jones. The senior Jones resided in Baltimore, at least during the early 1880s.
Arranged chronologically. Letters that do not clearly list a year are filed at the end of the collection.
No restrictions.
Finding aid available.
The collection was purchased using funds from the Joseph L. Arnold Library Endowment in April 2008 from M Benjamin Katz Fine Books/Manuscripts.
"Port Avon" (1878), "Morning on the Severn River" (1873), "A Quiet Morning" (1873), "Twilight on Bear Creek, Baltimore County" (1874), and "Near Union Bridge, Carroll County" (1873) by Hugh Bolton Jones, John William McCoy Collection, George Peabody Library, Peabody Institute of The Johns Hopkins University (Baltimore, MD).
"Landscape with Ducks," "Landscape," and "Autumn Landscape near Barrington, Vt." by Hugh Bolton Jones, Maryland Historical Society (Baltimore, MD).
Jones Laura; Jones Hugh Bolton 1848-1927; Landscape paintings; Paintings; Maryland; Baltimore (Md.)
- Series I. Hugh Bolton Jones letters, 1880-1881; 1 box (.5 linear feet)
  - May 1, 1880: Letter and Envelope (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - May 15, 1880: Letter and Envelope (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - [May 20, 1880]: Letter and Envelope (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - [May 22, 1880]: Envelope (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - August 31, 1880: Letter and Envelope (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - September 3, 1880: Letter and Envelope (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - October 8, 1880: Letter and Envelope (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - October 8, 1880: Letter and Envelope (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - October 13, 1880: Letter and Envelope (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - [November 18, 1880]: Envelope (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - [November 26, 1880]: Letter and Envelope (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - [April 11, 1881]: Envelope (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - April 12, 1881: Letter and Envelope (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - [April 16, 1881]: Letter and Envelope (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - [June 7, 1881]: Letter and Envelope (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - June 11, 1881: Letter and Envelope (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - June 20, 1881: Letter and Envelope (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - June 24, 1881: Letter and Envelope (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - August 23, 1881: Letter and Envelope (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - October 4, 1881: Letter and Envelope (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - [October 14, 1881]: Letter and Envelope (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - October 6, 1881: Letter and Envelope (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - October 24, 1881: Letter and Envelope (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - April 11, (no year): Envelope, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - [June 29, ?]: Envelope, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - December 2, (no year): Letter and Envelope, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)